Noman Sattar

Address: c-2/2 block 2 baloch goth block 13-d/3 gulshan-e-iqbal, karachi

Phone: +92 3047179647 Email: nomansattar47@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A passionate software engineer that develops server side applications. I have worked in project based environment in SCRUM mode of agile Development. Recognizing the bottlenecks and optimizing where ever is necessary is kind of my specialty. Over the years I have evolved to a person that just does not write optimized and secure code but also know how technology works from inside.

WORK EXPERIENCE 07/2021 - Present

Software Engineer, Express News.

Responsibilities:

- Dynamic Web Development using Laravel
- Develop Web Based Business Application
- Web Development using WordPress
- API Integration/Development
- Design and Develop UI using Android

12/2019 - 06/2021

Software Engineer, Inspedium Corp.

Responsibilities:

- Dynamic Web Development using PHP
- Develop Web Based Business Application
- Web Designing
- API Integration/Development

12/2018 - 10/2019

Web Developer, Plush Event Planning, U.S.A

Responsibilities:

- Web Designing
- Dynamic Web Development using PHP
- Social Media Strategist, Posting and managing social media accounts

EDUCATION 2019

BSCS, Iqra University North Karachi

2013

H.S.C, Govt. Degree College

CERTIFICATION 2020

Full Stack Web and Mobile Developer, UIT

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Database: MySQL, NoSQL (Firebase), SQL Server **Programming**: PHP, JavaScript, Java, Kotlin

Framework: Laravel

Web Designing: HTML, CSS, JQuery

Graphic Designing Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD

PROJECTS

ExpressPK Backend, Laravel 8:

ExpressPK backend for content management for the frontend site of express.pk

Edtutor CMS Backend, Laravel 8:

Edtutor CMS for content management for the frontend site of mobile app

Edtutor.pk, Wordpress:

https://edtutor.pk

Edtutor.pk is a E-Learning platform that provide students all over Pakistan with access to interactive and quality learning material from anywhere at any time.

EdTutor, Android:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.edtech.edt utor

EdTutor has been developed by the best Teachers in each Subject, the words in the text books have been transformed into 2D and 3D Animated videos with graphics to make the lessons not only fun but are also interactive. It develops their cognitive skills and strengthens their core concepts and deepens their knowledge of the subject.

EdTutor Parent App, Android:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.edtech.edt utorparentapp

EdTutor's Parent App is one of a kind, providing a means for parents to stay up to date on what their children are learning. It equips a parent, with the right set of tools, to track and monitor the student's learning progress, from anywhere in the world.

Facility Management System, Laravel 8:

https://shaheen-services.com/facility-management/login
Facility Management System is a complaint system that
includes ticket management. The customer raises his
complaint and company representative responds to the ticket.
The ticket can be assigned to the team and the dedicated team

updates the final status of the complaint.

Reliance Medical LAB, PHP 7:

Deployed at Local VPN

Reliance Medical Lab is an automated web application for a medical lab in Islamabad. This system automates all their daily medical process. Hardware like biometric, camera, passport scanner and barcode printer are also integrated in this system.

GSDCP (German Shepherd Dog Club Pakistan), Laravel 7: https://www.gsdcp.org/

GSDCP is an official web based portal which includes all Club process including accounts and ledger of member.

Dosari Shadi, Laravel 7, PHP 7, Android and Rest API: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ali.sangam Sangam.PK is a marriage consultant mobile application that find matches. The user send gifts, ask for number, start conversation, buy coin packages, and get push notifications And Admin portal that deals with all the maintenance/changes of mobile application.

REFERENCES

References available on request